

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Samrat Chopra Samrat Chopra Reatured 7 Certified Scrum Master Client Support Manager workinh as business analyst seeking assignment in Software Development, Mobile Application Development, Website development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, BRD, FRD, SRS, MS Visio, Jira, Azure, SQL, MySql

Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Highest Degree: PG Diploma [travel and tourism]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Designation: Client Support Manager - Business

Analyst

Current Company: One Store India

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore. Delhi / NCR. Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Client Support Manager, Business Analyst, Software Development, Mobile Application Development, Website development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Development, BRD, FRD, SRS, MS

Visio,Jira,Azure,SQL,MySql,PowerBl,Tableau

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects | Work Authorization

Summary

ACertified ScrumMaster® (CSM®) with 5.5 years of work experience in Business Development, Mobile Application development, Website development, E-Commerce & CRM

Elicitation, requirement gathering & stakeholder collaboration

Experience in Agile Scrum & Waterfall technology of implementation for software development

- * Preparing BRD,FRD & SRS(Business Documentation)
- * Preparing UML's, Wire- framing and prototypes Communicate requirements and updates of the same to the relevant stakeholder
- * Conduct and take part in Daily Scrum meeting.
- * Coordinate and participate in User Acceptance Testing

Work Experience

One Store India as Client Support Manager - Business Analyst May 2020 to Till Date

Conducting interviews & brainstorming sessions with internal stakeholders for validating the Business requirements

*Perform Impact analysis on new requirements to avoid any unseen errors

*Perform risk analysis to avoid unforseen roadblocks/impediments that may occur in future

*Checking all the parameters for a successful user story ie Definition of Done, Definition of Ready & User Acceptence

* Communicating process changes, enhancements, and modifications to team.

Worked effectively with cross-functional teams to ensure clear communication and outline of project requirements *Perform data analysis and utilizing * SQL query tools

Virtual Employee as Senior Executive - Business Analyst Mar 2017 to Mar 2020

Analyze and Synthesize information elicited from stakeholders and translate requirements into different deliverables such as functional specification, user stories & workflow diagrams to meet business needs and objectives.

*Conducted interviews, brainstorming sessions, workshops & joint application development sessions with internal and

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

external stakeholders in making sure the business requirements are validated and accomplished regularly.

- *Produce detailed Mockups & Wire-framing with versatile tools such as Ms-visio, Draw.io and balasmiq.
- * Working on defects/bugs/issues and coordinating with developers and QA
- * Write Test Cases, create RACI Matrix & Traceability Matrix
- * Supporting UAT and bug fixes during UAT
- EnP as Business Development Manager Feb 2015 to Jan 2017

Act as a liaison between business & technology group to facilitate communication both ways

- *Established relationships with key decision-makers within customer's organization to promote growth and retention.
- *Business development analysis to identify key products, services and customer base to devise innovative sales and
- *Earned promotion due to exemplary work to become the Business Development Manager.
- * Represented company and promoted products at conferences and trade association meetings.
- * Comprehensive MIS & CRM management.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Delhi college of Technology and management in 2014

PG: PG Diploma (travel and tourism) from KOUNI Academy - Defence Colony in 2014

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Sql Server 2008, MySQL		
JIRA		
MS PowerPoint, MS Excel		
MS Visio-2016, Draw.io		
Moqups		
TABLEAU		
As Is - To Be		
Waterfall, Agile		
Ms word / Ms Excel / Ms PowerPoint		
UAT/BDT		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
French				

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: Website Development

Client: One Store India

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2020 - Till Date Project Location: Noida Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Role: Other Team Size: 10

Skill Used: Excel, azure, azure rp, frd, Use Cases, Prototyping

Role Description: *Requirement elicitation, requirement gathering & stakeholder collaboration

*Preparing GRD & FRD/SRS

* Functional/Non-functional requirements

*Preparing UML's, Wire-framing and prototypes

*Take part in Daily Scrum meeting.

Project Details: Onemonitar.com is a website application created on WordPress CMS. As per project scope, a new ticket system was developed on Laravel CMS to overcome client's complaint's/issues and Laravel was integrated with WordPress.

Project Title: Marketing Portal Development

Client: Confidential

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2019 - Dec 2019 Project Location: USA Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Other Team Size: 8

Skill Used: JIRA, Prototype, Wireframing, UML, Documentation,

Role Description: *Requirement elicitation, requirement gathering & stakeholder collaboration

*Preparing BRD & SRS(Business Documentation)

*Preparing UML's, Wire- framing and prototypes

*Conduct and take part in Daily Scrum meeting.

Project Details: The company used to have an old SAP system which was non - customizable and quite expensive to capture leads and functionality.

The company wanted to develop their own crm project. Therefore, we implemented our customized crm tool capture leads, marketing campaigns and customer management.

Project Title: E-commerce Website & CRM development

Client: Protein World

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: UK
Project Location: UK
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Role: Other
Duration: Apr 2018 - Aug 2018
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 7

Skill Used: Agile Methodology, Scrum Master, Process Flow Diagram, JIRA, Prototype, Wireframing Role Description: *Requirement elicitation, requirement gathering & stakeholder collaboration

*Preparing BRD & SRS(Business Documentation)
*Preparing UM.'s, Wire- framing and prototypes
*Conduct and take part in Daily Scrum meeting.

Project Details: E-commerce Website:

The business objective was to create a secure, efficient & responsive website.

The website was earlier built on Joomla which was an inefficient CMS which has complex architecture, limited add-ons and modules for website customization. We

developed an efficient & user friendly website on WordPress.

CRM Module:

To provide operational CRM module which includes Sales automation, Marketing automation and Service automation.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India
Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.